<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mark Braverman on Mark Braverman's Home Page</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Mark Braverman on Mark Braverman's Home Page</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mbraverm.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brief Bio</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/brief-bio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/brief-bio/</guid><description>I received my PhD in 2008 from the Department of Computer Science at the University of Toronto under the supervision of Stephen Cook.
In 2007, together with Alex Hertel and Philipp Hertel, I co-founded Zetawire. It was acquired by Google from stealth mode in 2010, and formed the base for the Google Wallet product.
Between 2008 and 2010 I spent two years as a postdoctoral researcher at the Microsoft Research New England lab.</description></item><item><title>Members</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/team/members/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/team/members/</guid><description>Current Group Members Graduate students: Antonio Molina Lovett Postdocs: Vijay Bhattiprolu John Peebles Sahil Singla Alumni: With first place of employment/study:
Graduate students Sumegha Garg PhD in Computer Science, Princeton, 2020; Rabin Postdoctoral Fellow at Harvard. Young Kun Ko PhD in Computer Science, Princeton, 2018; Assistant Professor / Faculty Fellow at NYU. Jieming Mao PhD in Computer Science, Princeton, 2018; Google Research New York. Jonathan Schneider, PhD in Computer Science, Princeton, 2018; Google Research New York.</description></item><item><title>Affiliations and service</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/affiliations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/affiliations/</guid><description> Princeton Computer Science Theory Group PACM (Program in Applied and Computational Mathematics) Simons Institute for the Theory of Computing Scientific Advisory Board Foundations of Computational Mathematics Board of Directors</description></item><item><title>Joining the group</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/team/joining-the-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/team/joining-the-group/</guid><description>Thank you for you interest in joining the group!
Unfortunately, due to large volumes of email, I am not able to respond to individual inquiries about joining Princeton or our group. Some general details can be found below.
High school and undergraduate students If you are a Princeton undergrad, and are interested in the possibility of doing Junior/Senior independent work, please email me to make an appointment and discuss your interests.</description></item><item><title>Past projects</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/past-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/past-projects/</guid><description>This page is under construction.
Talks on complexity theory: A 15 minutes high level overview on theoretical computer science and information complexity: [pdf]
New bounds on the Grothendieck constant Let be an matrix. It gives rise to the quadratic form . The Grothendieck constant bounds the ratio between the maximum of this form when are unit vectors in a Hilbert space and the maximum of this form when are just real numbers.</description></item><item><title>Funding</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/funding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/funding/</guid><description>I gratefully acknowledge the following funding sources: Present: NSF, through the Alan T. Waterman award CCF-1933331 The Simons Foundation, through the Simons Collaboration on Algorithms and Geometry The David and Lucile Packard Foundation, through a Packard Fellowship Past: NSF, through award CCF-1525342: &amp;ldquo;Noise across computational settings&amp;rdquo; Princeton University, through an Alfred Rheinstein Faculty Award NSF, through CAREER award CCF-1149888: &amp;ldquo;Coding and information theory for interactive computing&amp;rdquo; NSF, through award CCF-1215990: &amp;ldquo;Collaborative Research: Data-driven mechanisms in healthcare&amp;rdquo; (joint with Mohsen Bayati from Stanford) The John Templeton Foundation, through a Turing Fellowship, which was part of &amp;ldquo;The Turing Centenary Research Project - Mind, Mechanism and Mathematics&amp;rdquo; NSF, through the Center for Computational Intractability The Alfred P.</description></item><item><title>Postdoc opportunities</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/team/postdoc-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/team/postdoc-opportunities/</guid><description>We have several exciting postdoctoral opportunities in Princeton and the area.
Princeton CS Theory group: Please see Princeton academic jobs portal here, and navigate to opportunities in Computer Science. The Theory Group typically advertises a postdoctoral research associate position and an associate research scholar position, which is slightly more senior. Both positions are reviewed in the late Fall, with the goal of making decisions by January/February.
IAS Membership: More information here.</description></item><item><title>Writings</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/writings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/writings/</guid><description>An essay on the need for personal digital advocates (Last updated: December 2020)
Abstract: There is a growing power imbalance between companies who have access to powerful algorithms and processing capacity and users who don’t. To restore the balance, we need to put equally powerful algorithms in the hands of individuals. There are two concrete steps we recommend:
(1) there should be a new regulatory framework which creates an unbreakable commitment for an advocate (a digital service) to work exclusively in the interest of its client;</description></item><item><title>All Papers</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/all-papers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/all-papers/</guid><description>Selected recent publications Network coding in undirected graphs is either very helpful or not helpful at all
Mark Braverman, Sumegha Garg, Ariel Schvartzman
[arXiv]
Parallel algorithms for select and partition with noisy comparisons
Mark Braverman, Jieming Mao, Matt Weinberg
STOC'16; [arXiv]
Interpolating between truthful and non-truthful mechanisms for combinatorial auctions
Mark Braverman, Jieming Mao, Matt Weinberg
SODA'16; [arXiv]
Constant-rate coding for multiparty interactive communication is impossible</description></item><item><title>Book</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/book/</guid><description>Book: Computability of Julia Sets
Mark Braverman, Michael Yampolsky
Springer, 2009
[Amazon] [Springer]</description></item><item><title>Undergraduate projects</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/team/undergraduate-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/team/undergraduate-projects/</guid><description>2015-16: Esther Rolf &amp;lsquo;16, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Capturing multiparty communication: extending notions of information theory to topology-dependent multiparty problems&amp;rdquo; Michael Yitayew &amp;lsquo;16, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Short-circuit error resilience in Boolean formulas&amp;rdquo; Zhongxia (Ricky) Zhao &amp;lsquo;16, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Non-clearing and combinatorial Walrasian equilibria&amp;rdquo; Clement Lee &amp;lsquo;17, F15, &amp;ldquo;Fast polynomial factorization&amp;rdquo; Blair Wang &amp;lsquo;17, F15, &amp;ldquo;Discovery of spurious statistical relationships&amp;rdquo; 2014-15: David Durst &amp;lsquo;15, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Beyond3D: Visualizing high-dimensional data sets&amp;rdquo; James Pinkerton &amp;lsquo;15, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Energy function arguments in finding Tower of Majority lower bounds&amp;rdquo; 2013-14: Andra Constantinescu &amp;lsquo;14, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Behavioral mechanism design - accounting for the mental cost of choosing&amp;rdquo; Mihai Roman &amp;lsquo;14, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Computational complexity of pricing derivatives&amp;rdquo; Leonardo Stedile &amp;lsquo;14, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Primal-dual based weights and other kidney exchange mechanisms&amp;rdquo; Valentina Barboy &amp;lsquo;15, F13, &amp;ldquo;An exploration of the accuracy and efficiency of peer grading&amp;rdquo; Stefani Karp &amp;lsquo;15, S14, &amp;ldquo;Information-theoretic approaches to the Unexpected Hanging Paradox&amp;rdquo; Christoph Schlom &amp;lsquo;15, S14, &amp;ldquo;Calibration testing&amp;rdquo; 2012-13: Kevin Mantel &amp;lsquo;13, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Election manipulation through misrepresentation of pre-election polls&amp;rdquo; Gal Oshri &amp;lsquo;13, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;Contracting experts with unknown cost structures&amp;rdquo; Kanika Pasricha, Thesis, &amp;ldquo;The computational hardness of pricing compound securities&amp;rdquo; Ashish Gupta &amp;lsquo;13, F12, &amp;ldquo;An investigation of the usefulness of data preprocessing techniques versus algorithmic sophistication on diabetes prediction&amp;rdquo; Leonardo Stedile &amp;lsquo;14, F12, &amp;ldquo;Analysis of risk in chess&amp;rdquo; Xiao Tian (Elaine) Liew &amp;lsquo;14, F12, &amp;ldquo;Effect of network structure on PageRank of spam&amp;rdquo; Xin Yang Yak &amp;lsquo;14, S13, &amp;ldquo;Do YouTube users upvote Better Comments?</description></item><item><title>Math has been enabled</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/posts/math-enabled/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/posts/math-enabled/</guid><description>Math is now enabled:
Inline math: $$ \varphi = \dfrac{1+\sqrt5}{2}= 1.6180339887… $$
Block math:
$$ \varphi = 1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\frac{1} {1+\cdots} } } $$</description></item><item><title>New Website</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/posts/new-website/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/posts/new-website/</guid><description>I created my new website using Hugo and GeekDocs!</description></item></channel></rss>