<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Mark Braverman's Home Page</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Mark Braverman's Home Page</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://mbraverm.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Past projects</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/past-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/past-projects/</guid><description>This page is under construction.
Talks on complexity theory: A 15 minutes high level overview on theoretical computer science and information complexity: [pdf]
New bounds on the Grothendieck constant Let be an matrix. It gives rise to the quadratic form . The Grothendieck constant bounds the ratio between the maximum of this form when are unit vectors in a Hilbert space and the maximum of this form when are just real numbers.</description></item><item><title>Writings</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/writings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/writings/</guid><description>An essay on the need for personal digital advocates (Last updated: December 2020)
Abstract: There is a growing power imbalance between companies who have access to powerful algorithms and processing capacity and users who don’t. To restore the balance, we need to put equally powerful algorithms in the hands of individuals. There are two concrete steps we recommend:
(1) there should be a new regulatory framework which creates an unbreakable commitment for an advocate (a digital service) to work exclusively in the interest of its client;</description></item><item><title>All Papers</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/all-papers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/all-papers/</guid><description>Selected recent publications Network coding in undirected graphs is either very helpful or not helpful at all
Mark Braverman, Sumegha Garg, Ariel Schvartzman
[arXiv]
Parallel algorithms for select and partition with noisy comparisons
Mark Braverman, Jieming Mao, Matt Weinberg
STOC'16; [arXiv]
Interpolating between truthful and non-truthful mechanisms for combinatorial auctions
Mark Braverman, Jieming Mao, Matt Weinberg
SODA'16; [arXiv]
Constant-rate coding for multiparty interactive communication is impossible</description></item><item><title>Book</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/book/</guid><description>Book: Computability of Julia Sets
Mark Braverman, Michael Yampolsky
Springer, 2009
[Amazon] [Springer]</description></item></channel></rss>