<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Mark Braverman's Home Page</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Mark Braverman's Home Page</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://mbraverm.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamics and computation</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/dynamics-and-computation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/dynamics-and-computation/</guid><description>A dynamical system is a stateful system (often with a continuous state space) evolving over time. Thus, dynamical systems can be (and are being) used to capture the behavior of both natural and articifical systems over time. The state space of dynamical systems is typically continuous, which means that one has to look at continuous models of computation. Here is a short 2013 Communications of the ACM article I wrote explaining computation over the reals.</description></item><item><title>Information complexity</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/information-complexity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/information-complexity/</guid><description>Information theory is a vastly successful theory underpinning much of our communication technology. In many important communication scenarios it allows one to calculate the precise amount of resources needed to perform a cetrain task. For example, the number of bits Alice needs to communicate to send a string $x_1 x_2 \ldots x_n$ of $n$ random trits (elements from $\lbrace 1,2,3\rbrace$) to Bob is given by $(\log_2 3) \cdot n \pm o(n)$.</description></item><item><title>Mechanism design</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/mech-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/mech-design/</guid><description>Black-box reductions from algorithms to mechanisms without money Strategic capitation: mechanism design in the &amp;ldquo;big data&amp;rdquo; regime Mechanism design for learning agents Overview Algorithm design vs. mechanism design. The starting point of Algorithm design is a specified input-output behavior: $L$ is a list of numbers, and $SORT(L)$ is the same list sorted in ascending order; $f$ is boolean formula, and $SAT(f)$ is a satisfying assignment &amp;ndash; if one exists; $D$ is a list of labeled examples, and $Model(D)$ is a trained model for labeling previously unseed examples.</description></item><item><title>Misc projects</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/past-projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/past-projects/</guid><description>Contents New bounds on the Grothendieck constant Monotonicity and implementability New bounds on the Grothendieck constant Let $A$ be an $n\times n$ matrix. It gives rise to the quadratic form $$\sum_{i,j} A_{ij} x_i y_j.$$ The Grothendieck constant $k$ bounds the ratio between the maximum of this form when $x_i,y_j$ are unit vectors in a Hilbert space and the maximum of this form when $x_i,y_j\in {-1,1}$ are just real numbers. In other words, $k$ is the smallest number such that for all $A$,</description></item><item><title>Writings</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/writings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/writings/</guid><description>An essay on the need for personal digital advocates (Last updated: December 2020)
Abstract: There is a growing power imbalance between companies who have access to powerful algorithms and processing capacity and users who don’t. To restore the balance, we need to put equally powerful algorithms in the hands of individuals. There are two concrete steps we recommend:
(1) there should be a new regulatory framework which creates an unbreakable commitment for an advocate (a digital service) to work exclusively in the interest of its client;</description></item><item><title>All Papers</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/all-papers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/research/all-papers/</guid><description>Selected recent publications and preprints Optimization-friendly generic mechanisms without money
Mark Braverman
[arXiv] [talk]
Statistically near-optimal hypothesis selection
Olivier Bousquet, Mark Braverman, Klim Efremenko, Gillat Kol, Shay Moran
FOCS'21; [arXiv]
Tight space complexity of the coin problem
Mark Braverman, Sumegha Garg, Or Zamir
FOCS'21; [ECCC]
Data-driven incentive alignment in capitation schemes
Mark Braverman, Sylvain Chassang
[NBER preprint] [Journal of Public Economics 207, 2022]
BeauCoup: Answering many network traffic queries, one memory update at a time</description></item></channel></rss>