<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Mark Braverman's Home Page</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Mark Braverman's Home Page</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://mbraverm.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brief Bio</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/brief-bio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/brief-bio/</guid><description>I received my PhD in 2008 from the Department of Computer Science at the University of Toronto under the supervision of Stephen Cook.
In 2007, together with Alex Hertel and Philipp Hertel, I co-founded Zetawire. It was acquired by Google from stealth mode in 2010, and formed the base for the Google Wallet product.
Between 2008 and 2010 I spent two years as a postdoctoral researcher at the Microsoft Research New England lab.</description></item><item><title>Affiliations</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/affiliations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/affiliations/</guid><description> Princeton Computer Science Theory Group Center for Computational Intractability Economic Theory Center PACM (Program in Applied and Computational Mathematics)</description></item><item><title>Funding</title><link>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/funding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mbraverm.github.io/about/funding/</guid><description>I gratefully acknowledge the following funding sources: Present: NSF, through the Alan T. Waterman award CCF-1933331 The Simons Foundation, through the Simons Collaboration on Algorithms and Geometry The David and Lucile Packard Foundation, through a Packard Fellowship Past: NSF, through award CCF-1525342: &amp;ldquo;Noise across computational settings&amp;rdquo; Princeton University, through an Alfred Rheinstein Faculty Award NSF, through CAREER award CCF-1149888: &amp;ldquo;Coding and information theory for interactive computing&amp;rdquo; NSF, through award CCF-1215990: &amp;ldquo;Collaborative Research: Data-driven mechanisms in healthcare&amp;rdquo; (joint with Mohsen Bayati from Stanford) The John Templeton Foundation, through a Turing Fellowship, which was part of &amp;ldquo;The Turing Centenary Research Project - Mind, Mechanism and Mathematics&amp;rdquo; NSF, through the Center for Computational Intractability The Alfred P.</description></item></channel></rss>